Guide to the Dana Tai Soon Burgess Dance Company records, 1988-2012 MS2030
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Administrative files, 1988-2006; MS2030 Series 3
  - Organizational information, biographies, histories, current and future programs, undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Moving Forward Dance Company Website (printout), 2001 January 06 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Contracts & finances, undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Fellowship applications, 1995-1999 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Publicity shots, Burgess, undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Step Afrika, undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Movable Fundraiser to benefit Moving Forward Dance Company, 1998 December 09 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Asian Pacific American Institute for Congressional Studies, Sixth Annual Gala Dinner, 2000 May 25 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Teaching activities, undated (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Panel discussion - "Asian American Expression in the Arts", 1995 January 21 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Postcard of Paul Cadmus' "Árabesque," 9" x 6", undated (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Newspaper clippings, 1988-2012; MS2030 Series 4
  This series consists of newspaper clippings about Dana Tai Soon Burgess and Moving Forward: Asian American Dance Company. These articles date from 1988 to 2012.
  - New Mexico clippings, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1990-1993 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1994-1995 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1996-1997 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1998-2000 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Newspaper clippings, 2001-2006 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Newspaper clippings, 2008-2009; Series 4 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Mongolia, 2011 March; Series 4 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Charlie Chan, 2011 April; Series 4 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - "Becoming American", 2011 October; Series 4 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Dance Plate PR, 2011-2012; Series 4 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Huffington Post, 2012 April; Series 4 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - 20th Season Performance, 2012 April; Series 4 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Campany Articles, 2012 April-March; Series 4 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - A.A. Youth Movement, 2012 May; Series 4 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Kennedy Center, 2012 May; Series 4 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Smithsonian, 2012 May; Series 4 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Jordan, 2012 May; Series 4 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Newspaper clippings, undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Audiovisual material, 1992-2009; MS2030 Series 5
  This series consists of photographs and videocassettes of solo performances by Dana Tai Soon Burgess, as well as performances by Moving Forward and the summer youth program. The bulk of the series is the videocassettes, which are divided by format into VHS and Master Broadcasting. Within each format, the cassettes are arranged chronologically by performance. The series also includes one DVD.
  - Photograph: 8 x 10 black and white, Dana Tai Soon Burgess, undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Photograph: 8 x 10 black and white, Unidentified female, photographed by Javier Gracia, undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Photograph: Michio Ito, 8 x 10 black and white, photographed by Toyo Miyataki, Circa 1929 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Photograph: Black and white, 8 x 10, Dana Tai Soon Burgess and female dancer, undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Photograph: Black and white, 8 x 10, unidentified male, undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Photograph: Color, 8 x 10, Dana Tai Soon Burgess and female dancer with American flag, undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Photograph: Black and white, 4 x 6, female dancer, undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Photograph: Black and white, 8 x 10, female dancer on stage, undated (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Photograph: Black and white, 4 x 6, female dancer on stage with pineapple, undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Photograph: Color, 4 x 6, September 27, 1994, 1994 September 27 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Photograph: Color, 3 x 5, September 27, 1994, 1994 September 27 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Videocassette: "The Boy Inside the Man," Dana Tai Soon Burgess, undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Videocassette: Fox and Temple Performance (?), 1992 November 18 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Videocassette: Fox and Temple rehearsal, Circa 1992 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Videocassette: WPA Re-Voltaire "Disoriental in DC," Dana Tai Soon Burgess, 1992 December 18 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Videocassette: Dana Tai Soon Burgess, Dance Place, 1993 March 01 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Videocassette: Moving Forward, Latino American Dance Company, Keith Lee's Contemporary Art Performance, 1993 August 03-04 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Videocassette: "Searching for the Sun and Moon," Freer Gallery of Art, 1994 April 16 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Videocassette: Youth program rehearsal, Kennedy Center Theatre Lab, 1994 August 01 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Videocassette: Youth program rehearsal, Kennedy Center Theatre Lab, 1994 August 01 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Videocassette: Youth program performance, Kennedy Center Theatre Lab, 1994 August 01 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Videocassette: Youth program performance, Kennedy Center Theatre Lab, 1994 August 01 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Videocassette: Kennedy Center Front and Center! rehearsal, 1995 April (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Videocassette: "Abandoning the Promise," Passages from the Journey, Perspectives in Asian American Dance, National Portrait Gallery, 6 minutes 2 seconds, 1996 May 20 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Videocassette: "Tracings of Wehdoh," "Remembering Chinatown, DC", 1993 April (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Videocassettes: Maida Withers Dance Construction Company, "Recent Works", undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Videocassette: Unidentified rehearsal, undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Videocassette: Tracings of Wehdoh, 1993 April (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Videocassette: Joy of Motion in Concert 1995 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Videocassette: Moving Forward Summer 95 Kids, 1995 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Videocassette: Moving Forward Tom Ebb, 1995 September (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Videocassette: "The Supplicant", 1996 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Videocassette: Dana Tai Soon Burgess & Company, A Decade of Dance, Lincoln Theatre, 2002 October 05 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Videocassette: Dana Tai Soon Burgess Distance Dance Performance, undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Videocassette: Venezuela, undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Videocassette: Dana Burgess Dance at the Corcoran Art Gallery, undated (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Videocassette: Dana Tai Soon Burgess Close Up Dance Performance, undated (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Videocassette: Helix (2) - Transfer from Beta - Marianne Richards, undated (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Videocassette: Asians in the Americas, 1997 January 24-26 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Videocassette: Nightingale (Dana's recording), undated (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - DVD: Images from the Embers, 2006 March 03 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Master videocassette: "The Boy Inside the Man", 1992 April (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Master videocassette: "Searching for the Sun and Moon", 1994 April 16 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Master videocassette: 2nd annual summer youth program performance, Kennedy Center, 1994 August 01 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Master videocassette: Youth program rehearsal, Kennedy Center, 1994 August (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Master videocassette: Youth program rehearsal part 2 (tape 1), 1994 August (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Master videocassette: Youth program rehearsal part 2 (tape 2), 1994 August (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Master videocassette: Unidentified rehearsal, 1995 January 22 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Master videocassette: Close Up, Dance Place, 1995 January (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Master videocassette: Distance, Dance Place, 1995 January (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Master videocassette: Unknown performance dress rehearsal, Kennedy Center, 1995 April 13 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - DVD: Island and untitled, 2008 October 24-25 - 2009 October; Series 5 (Box 17, Folder 5)
- Oversize material, 1988-2006; MS2030 Series 6
  This series consists of material too large to be stored with the first five series. Included are posters, mounted material, such as letters and articles, and oversize publications.
  - Mounted program - Springtime Space, Rodey Theatre, University of New Mexico, 1988 March 30-April 08 (Oversize 13, Folder 1)
  - Mounted letter - to Dana Tai Soon Burgess from Judith Chazin-Bennahum, Head of the Dance Program at the University of New Mexico, 1988 October 21 (Oversize 13, Folder 2)
  - Mounted poster - Choreographer's Showcase, Center for Contemporary Arts, Albuquerque, NM, 1988 July 01-02 (Oversize 13, Folder 3)
  - Mounted program - Choreographer's Showcase, Center for Contemporary Arts, Albuquerque, NM, 1988 July 01-02 (Oversize 13, Folder 4)
  - Mounted article - Choreographer's Showcase, Center for Contemporary Arts, Albuquerque, NM, 1988 July 01-02 (Oversize 13, Folder 5)
  - Mounted program and article - Tim Wengerd and Company, Kimo Theatre, Albuquerque, NM, 1988 October 21-22 (Oversize 13, Folder 6)
  - Mounted article - Tim Wengerd and Company, Kimo Theatre, Albuquerque, NM, 1988 October 2122 (Oversize 13, Folder 7)
  - Mounted flyer - Summer Modern Repertory Dance Workshop, Hall of Nations Black Box Theatre, Georgetown University, 1990 August 10-12 (Oversize 13, Folder 8)
  - Mounted article - Books Alive, Martin Luther King, Jr. Library, undated (Oversize 13, Folder 9)
  - Newsletter - Rodey View, 1992 (Oversize 13, Folder 10)
  - Poster - Art at Risk, 1993-1994 (Oversize 13, Folder 11)
  - Washington Review, 1995 October-November (Oversize 13, Folder 12)
  - La Danza, 1996 July-December (Oversize 13, Folder 13)
  - Poster: Dance Concert, Marvin Center, George Washington University, 1997 April 24-26 (Oversize 13, Folder 14)
  - Poster: Decolonizing the Body: Asians/Asian Americans Seeking New Intersections of Gender, Race & Class, 1996 March-April (Oversize 13, Folder 15)
  - Poster: Helix, Corcoran Gallery of Art, Washington, DC, 1998 February 01-16 (Oversize 13, Folder 16)
  - The U.S.-Korea Review, 1998 March-April (Oversize 13, Folder 17)
  - Washington Review, 1998 August-September (Oversize 13, Folder 18)
  - Asides: A Publication of the Shakespeare Theatre, 1998-1999 (Oversize 13, Folder 19)
  - Washington Review, 1999 December-2000 January (Oversize 13, Folder 20)
  - Poster: Trilogy, 2001 December 07-08 (Oversize 13, Folder 21)
  - Washingtonians: A Calendar of Dancers, 2002 (Oversize 13, Folder 22)
  - Poster: Celebrating a Decade of Dance, 2002 October 05 (Oversize 13, Folder 23)